PRANSHU KUMAR

Student

My Contact

choudharypranshu1947@gmail.com

(+91 6209207993

Oarbhanga,Bihar-846009

https://www.linkedin.com/in/pr anshu-kumar-512a41215

Skills

- Java, Python
- DSA
- OOPs
- DBMS
- SQL
- Tableau
- Html, CSS, JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- ui/ux
- Data Science

Education Background

08/2021 - Current
 Vellore Institute Of Technology | Vellore, TN
 B.Tech: Computer Science
 Specialization in Bioinformatics
 CGPA: 8.61

06/2019-06/2021
 Public School Darbhanga | Darbhanga, BR
 Higher Secondary: Science - PCM | CBSE

03/2007-04/2019

 Madonna English School | Darbhanga, BR Secondary | ICSE

Hobbies

- Chess
- Travelling
- · Reading Books

Certifications

- Programming Foundations with JavaScript, HTML and CSS.
- Python for Machine Language
- Leadership skills from IIM Ahmedabad

About Me

I am currently pursuing my B. Tech in Computer Science from Vellore Institute of Technology, with a specialization in Bioinformatics. I am actively utilizing my technical and analytical skills to increase my knowledge in the field. I am working hard to gain the maximum benefit from this program, and I am confident that my studies will help me achieve success in the future.

Experience

14/08/2023-13/10/2023

Intern

Schneider Electric | Bengaluru

- Cybersecurity Dashboard Project
- Cybersecurity Frameworks
- Data Science Project

03/2022-Current

Senior core member

Mozilla Firefox club | VIT Vellore, India

- Design Domain
- Coordinated activities and communicated information among the board, external auditors and management.

03/2022-Current

Senior core member

IEEE EMBS Chapter | VIT Vellore, India

- Design And Management Domains
- Coordinated activities and communicated information among the board, external auditors and management.

02/2023-03/2023

Social Worker

Hamari Pahachan NGO | New Delhi, India

03/2022-04/2022

Campus Ambassador

IIT Delhi | New Delhi, India

Project

- Tableau sales Dashboard
- Portfolio website (https://github.com/Pranshu1947/OIBSIP)

Achievements

- 5 star Java, Python coder on HackerRank
- Gold Medalist in Forest and their management course by IIT Kanpur